<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>EuRuKo 2013 Blog</title>
  <subtitle>The European Ruby Conference 2013 Blog</subtitle>
  <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog</id>
  <link href="http://euruko2013.org/blog"/>
  <link href="http://euruko2013.org/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-04-30T20:38:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EuRuKo 2013</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The why, the how and what’s next for the CfP</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-30-the-why-the-how-and-what-s-next-for-the-cfp/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-30-the-why-the-how-and-what-s-next-for-the-cfp/</id>
    <published>2013-04-30T20:38:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-30T20:38:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we first started organizing EuRuKo 2013 we made the following question to ourselves:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the most important aspects of the conference?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and we all agreed on the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality of presentations&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Socializing and friendly atmosphere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we first started organizing EuRuKo 2013 we made the following question to ourselves:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the most important aspects of the conference?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and we all agreed on the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality of presentations&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Socializing and friendly atmosphere&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything else follows and is of lower priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We handled the second early in the process by putting a lot of effort in trying to find the best possible venue without exceeding the budget. And we believe we really nailed it! Then it was time to find the best possible solution to the most important aspect of the conference: the presentations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before continuing, we should mention that EuRuKo is a special kind of event: it’s non-profit and organized by the community for the community. This means it carries some special opportunities but also many special challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='goals'&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we wanted to achieve is simple: high quality of presentations from the most diverse possible team of presenters. We don’t believe that these two are contradictory, quite the opposite, the one re-enforces the other. Still though, there were some challenges that needed to be faced:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage proposal submission by everyone (including “newbies”, minorities, etc)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Encourage refinements on proposals&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the selection process is neutral, fair and unbiased&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Make sure that the most interesting proposals are actually selected by the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id='and'&gt;And&amp;#8230;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you &lt;a href='/blog/2013-03-28-call-for-presentations/'&gt;should&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='/blog/2013-04-13-ten-days-before-the-cfp-closes-and/'&gt;already&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='/blog/2013-04-22-oh-my-cfp-submissions-coming-to-an-end-what-s-next-stats-and-more/'&gt;have&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href='/blog/2013-04-28-taking-off-the-cfp-masks-the-ones-who-made-it-in-the-shortlist/'&gt;noticed&lt;/a&gt; the CfP process was a rather long and community driven process so far. It took more than &lt;em&gt;500 registered users&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;250 suggestions&lt;/em&gt;, almost &lt;em&gt;3.000 casted votes&lt;/em&gt; and something less than &lt;em&gt;30.000 impressions&lt;/em&gt; to come up with &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;30 astonishing proposals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; that made it to the shortlist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These 30 proposals will now give one last eponymous fight in order to be presented during EuRuKo 2013. And let’s not forget all those other proposals that didn’t make it: most of them (if not all of them) could be easily chosen instead. If you check the ratings, the numbers are amazingly close. And this is where the ranking algorithm comes in&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='how_did_the_proposals_get_chosen'&gt;How did the proposals get chosen?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we answer this question, let’s answer the following ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What constitutes a good indication of interestingness?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;What makes a bad indication of interestingness?&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;What makes a bad judge?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a little simplyfication, here are some answers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good indications of interestingness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engagement&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Popularity&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Explicit preference&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ratios instead of absolute raw numbers (or vanity metrics)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad indications of interestingness&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bad data&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Easily exploitable data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad judges&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unfair and/or biased to specific proposals or authors&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Irrelevant to the domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s go back to the original question: &lt;em&gt;how did the proposals get chosen?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First of all the ingredients (a.k.a the metrics):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ratio of “upvotes” to total votes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ratio of unique user impressions for a specific proposal (a.k.a. how many users viewed this proposal) to total unique user impressions for all proposals (a.k.a. how many users viewed at least one proposal)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then the recipe (a.k.a the algorithm):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculate the confidence interval for the votes ratio using the Wilson score interval&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Do the same for the impressions ratio&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Weight them giving a heavy preference to votes over impressions&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sum them up&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Rank the proposals based on the above number&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Select the first 30 proposals from unique authors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And the special secret spice (a.k.a the exceptions):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before executing the recipe, exclude users with very little engagement in order to not skew the results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id='whats_next'&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it’s the time we define the final lineup for EuRuKo 2013. We choose the exact 10 talks we would like to see in order of preference. We organise a really awesome conference. And by saying ‘we’, we mean the delegates, the organisers, the volunteers, the supporters, the sponsors and all the ruby community which will watch or read the presentations online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.: Tickets won’t be available for much longer, so &lt;a href='https://www.eventora.com/en/Events/euruko-2013-athens'&gt;grab yours now&lt;/a&gt; and come to Athens for an awesome summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='references'&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binomial_proportion_confidence_interval'&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Binomial_proportion_confidence_interval&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.ucl.ac.uk/english-usage/staff/sean/resources/binomialpoisson.pdf'&gt;http://www.ucl.ac.uk/english-usage/staff/sean/resources/binomialpoisson.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.evanmiller.org/how-not-to-sort-by-average-rating.html'&gt;http://www.evanmiller.org/how-not-to-sort-by-average-rating.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://possiblywrong.wordpress.com/2011/06/05/reddits-comment-ranking-algorithm/'&gt;http://possiblywrong.wordpress.com/2011/06/05/reddits-comment-ranking-algorithm/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://amix.dk/blog/post/19588'&gt;http://amix.dk/blog/post/19588&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://blog.reddit.com/2009/10/reddits-new-comment-sorting-system.html'&gt;http://blog.reddit.com/2009/10/reddits-new-comment-sorting-system.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/euruko2013/vestibule/blob/master/app/models/proposal.rb'&gt;https://github.com/euruko2013/vestibule/blob/master/app/models/proposal.rb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Taking off the CfP masks: the ones who made it in the shortlist</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-28-taking-off-the-cfp-masks-the-ones-who-made-it-in-the-shortlist/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-28-taking-off-the-cfp-masks-the-ones-who-made-it-in-the-shortlist/</id>
    <published>2013-04-28T20:59:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-28T20:59:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are like us then you just can’t wait to find out who was behind each proposal and which ones got shortlisted for your final vote! Even ourselves, the organisers, refrained from peeking at the database (yes, it wasn’t easy), so even we don’t...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you are like us then you just can’t wait to find out who was behind each proposal and which ones got shortlisted for your final vote! Even ourselves, the organisers, refrained from peeking at the database (yes, it wasn’t easy), so even we don’t know who is behind each proposal&amp;#8230; until now that is! :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had &lt;span&gt;91 outstanding proposals&lt;/span&gt; and we wish we could have many, many more of them presented than the 14 (plus a few lightning ones) we scheduled for the 2 days of the event. There are so many truly intriguing talks proposed that we wish we could do something about it. But, we can’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What should happen now is that everyone should carefully review the shortlist and vote for the ones that will make it for this summer’s event. Author names will be shown, voter names will also be shown, votes will be counted (and recounted if necessary), withdrawn proposal authors will be named and in general a lot of light will be shed on what is a fine assortment of Ruby themes and trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is up to all of us to craft the best EuRuKo programme ever made, for which we only have from tomorrow April 29th until the 5th of May to do so!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To stir things up, we also recommend that when you vote for your favourites proposals you also tweet about them using #euruko as the hashtag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals#nominations'&gt;have a look at the shortlist&lt;/a&gt; and make sure you &lt;a href='https://www.eventora.com/en/Events/euruko-2013-athens'&gt;grab a ticket before the voting ends&lt;/a&gt; because it probably will end too after that!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Oh my! CFP submissions coming to an end, what’s next, stats and more</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-22-oh-my-cfp-submissions-coming-to-an-end-what-s-next-stats-and-more/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-22-oh-my-cfp-submissions-coming-to-an-end-what-s-next-stats-and-more/</id>
    <published>2013-04-22T17:41:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-22T17:41:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Heroes are made and heroes are remembered. However, usually behind them lies an army of unsung supporters!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EuRuKo 2013 CfP process has three distinct parts. We have almost completed the first part (with great success) where proposed talk submissions...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Heroes are made and heroes are remembered. However, usually behind them lies an army of unsung supporters!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EuRuKo 2013 CfP process has three distinct parts. We have almost completed the first part (with great success) where proposed talk submissions took place. This year we had &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;72 amazing submissions&lt;/a&gt; (and this may get higher until tomorrow) which are a testament to the diverse and involved community we Rubyists enjoy. Unfortunately we can’t have them all this summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow we start with the second part of our CfP process. In this second part, &lt;em&gt;the interlude&lt;/em&gt; between Phase I and Phase II, you are called in &lt;strong&gt;5 days&lt;/strong&gt; to create a shortlist of &lt;strong&gt;30 proposed talks&lt;/strong&gt;. This is of utmost importance since this shortlist is going to be the one from which you will select the &lt;strong&gt;10 talks&lt;/strong&gt; for this summer’s event during the Phase II voting. &lt;strong&gt;If you don’t push your favourite proposal in the shortlist you won’t be able to vote for it later!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you can do to shape this shortlist is to go to the &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org'&gt;app&lt;/a&gt; and:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;promote&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;demote&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;share your favourite proposals on social networks so that many more get involved!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the time to rally behind your favourite proposals and, who knows, perhaps make someone (whose name you still don’t know) a new Ruby hero! &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org'&gt;Go shape this summer’s conference now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;P.S.: For the number lovers, here are some fresh ones:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/motivation'&gt;300+ users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;72 proposals&lt;/a&gt; (4 withdrawn)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Almost 200 suggestions&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;17000+ impressions&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;1200+ votes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And last but not least: &lt;strong&gt;you do have tickets don’t you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If not, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='https://www.eventora.com/en/Events/euruko-2013-athens'&gt;go grab’em now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet our sponsors: Metaquark</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-17-meet-our-sponsors-metaquark/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-17-meet-our-sponsors-metaquark/</id>
    <published>2013-04-17T09:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T09:55:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Metaquark Logo" src="/images/sponsors/metaquark_150x75.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the team at &lt;a href="http://metaquark.de/"&gt;Metaquark&lt;/a&gt; shared every mobile developer’s experience. This of the difficulty of designing, building, releasing and maintaining mobile apps. In this experience, many manual steps had to be followed repeatedly in order...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Metaquark Logo' src='/images/sponsors/metaquark_150x75.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the team at &lt;a href='http://metaquark.de/'&gt;Metaquark&lt;/a&gt; shared every mobile developer&amp;#8217;s experience. This of the difficulty of designing, building, releasing and maintaining mobile apps. In this experience, many manual steps had to be followed repeatedly in order to test, publish and then collect application usage information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It got more complicated every time they added support for a new mobile operating system, because none of them are alike as we all know. It got even worse when they tried to do all of that in a distributed team, with very few tools that were built to support such team structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was when when they set out to make developing mobile apps a lot easier. Metaquark&amp;#8217;s mobile enterprise application platform called ‘AppFresh Mobile’ is a central service for large and small companies which helps manage the life-cycle of mobile applications. AppFresh Mobile includes distributed cloud builds for all mobile platforms, application security policies, distribution of applications to handsets using a custom enterprise applications store and extensive monitoring to help improve the quality of applications delivered to employees and customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metaquark work with a great variety of technologies to implement their mobile cross-platform and cloud strategy. Not surprisingly, their core platform is powered by Ruby and Rails. Their platform can either be deployed in a highly scalable Metaquark cloud setup, or directly at the customer site. Metaquark are small but fast growing. Their team and their vision are backed by their strategic investor and strong partner Software AG. Together they deliver mobile technologies and projects for some of the biggest enterprises all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that, but Metaquark are &lt;a href='http://metaquark.de/jobs/'&gt;hiring!&lt;/a&gt; They suggest that if you&amp;#8217;re looking for a challenge, they are the right place for you! The place to work on technology, concepts and strategies, think in new ways, be creative and take over great challenges. You may join them in one of their offices in Berlin and Leipzig (Germany) and make cross-platform mobile application life-cycle management available to all enterprises which develop mobile applications. From managing, building and signing mobile applications in the cloud to full featured application and device management on the mobile client, you name it, they are working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help development teams all over the world develop better apps and save time by using AppFresh Mobile!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Calling All Ruby Brigades</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-17-calling-all-ruby-brigades/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-17-calling-all-ruby-brigades/</id>
    <published>2013-04-17T05:39:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T05:39:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first time I attended EuRuKo was 2008. I managed to get a talk accepted so I didn&amp;#8217;t have to worry about a ticket. Every year after that I fell victim to what I have recently seen called the &amp;#8220;EuRuKo ticket fight&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference is popular and...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first time I attended EuRuKo was 2008. I managed to get a talk accepted so I didn&amp;#8217;t have to worry about a ticket. Every year after that I fell victim to what I have recently seen called the &amp;#8220;EuRuKo ticket fight&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference is popular and tickets sell out in record speeds. It&amp;#8217;s a pleasant problem for a conference organizer, but we are not professional conference organizers! We are part of the community and have ourselves been subjected to the same frustration of not being able to secure a ticket for the conference we love. So we will introduce a couple of different ways to distribute tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of these is something our Dutch friends established last year for EuRuKo 2012: Tickets reserved for Ruby user groups. Interesting fact: Almost half of this year&amp;#8217;s organizing committee got tickets for the Amsterdam conference this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For EuRuKo 2013 there will be reserved tickets for Ruby user groups. If you are a member of a Ruby user group and would like tickets then please fill in the &lt;a href='https://docs.google.com/a/euruko2013.org/spreadsheet/viewform?formkey=dFhXcDQtQlQ5SGZJTDNzaEZCZEx5R1E6MQ'&gt;form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give us the name of the user group along the number of tickets you would like and any information that will help us verify your claim . The deadline for submissions is the 26th April. We cannot guarantee that you will get all the tickets you ask for and we do recommend to try and get your ticket from the last batch to go on sale &lt;a href='http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=EuRuKo+2013+3rd+ticket+batch%21&amp;amp;iso=20130419T17'&gt;Friday, April 19th at 17:00UTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there are requests for more tickets then the number we have reserved we will distrbute them evenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User groups are the heart of every local communitty and EuRuKo is the best venue for the local communities to connect, communicate and cooperate. Join us in making EuRuKo 2013 one of the best Ruby conferences!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet our sponsors: Avarteq</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-16-meet-our-sponsors-avarteq/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-16-meet-our-sponsors-avarteq/</id>
    <published>2013-04-16T10:49:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T10:49:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Avarteq Logo" src="/images/sponsors/avarteq_200x100.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anynines is an upcoming Heroku-like PaaS written in Ruby. A hosting that grows with your apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks from anynines see their job as terribly important - many developers put pet apps to PaaS providers, yet introducing larger installations is often...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Avarteq Logo' src='/images/sponsors/avarteq_200x100.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anynines is an upcoming Heroku-like PaaS written in Ruby. A hosting that grows with your apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks from anynines see their job as terribly important - many developers put pet apps to PaaS providers, yet introducing larger installations is often way too expensive and complicated. That’s why it’s going to start as non-freemium, pay-as-you-go service. Additionaly, one of anynines’ goals is to make PaaS both affordable and compliant to European privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you see, it’s more than just business. Anynines supports selected non-profit open source and charity projects with free hosting, being itself based on the CloudFoundry software! This will allow a fair cost-by-cause-based pricing while still returning something to the community. A sort of Fair Trade hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anynines is operated by enterprise-rails.com, a Rails-focused hosting service and a division of Avarteq. Enterprise-rails.com manages and runs your app in any environment - most customers simply leave the job up to to Enterprise Rails, including hardware and/or OpenStack virtualization, Chef installation automation, monitoring and backups. Just leave it to them and enjoy your apps running like a clockwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The engine behind anynines and enterprise-rails.com is &lt;a href='http://www.avarteq.de/?utm_source=euruko&amp;amp;utm_medium=banner&amp;amp;utm_campaign=selene'&gt;Avarteq&lt;/a&gt;, a German Ruby shop founded in late 2008. It’s been many projects since then and Avarteq has grown from 3 to over 30 people, becoming a rock solid organization with profound Ruby and Ruby on Rails knowledge for both development and operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avarteq loves EuRuKo and would do all their best to keep this magical event alive.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
