<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>EuRuKo 2013 Blog</title>
  <subtitle>The European Ruby Conference 2013 Blog</subtitle>
  <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog</id>
  <link href="http://euruko2013.org/blog"/>
  <link href="http://euruko2013.org/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-04-16T10:49:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EuRuKo 2013</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet our sponsors: Avarteq</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-16-meet-our-sponsors-avarteq/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-16-meet-our-sponsors-avarteq/</id>
    <published>2013-04-16T10:49:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T10:49:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Avarteq Logo" src="/images/sponsors/avarteq_200x100.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anynines is an upcoming Heroku-like PaaS written in Ruby. A hosting that grows with your apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks from anynines see their job as terribly important - many developers put pet apps to PaaS providers, yet introducing larger installations is often...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Avarteq Logo' src='/images/sponsors/avarteq_200x100.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anynines is an upcoming Heroku-like PaaS written in Ruby. A hosting that grows with your apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks from anynines see their job as terribly important - many developers put pet apps to PaaS providers, yet introducing larger installations is often way too expensive and complicated. That’s why it’s going to start as non-freemium, pay-as-you-go service. Additionaly, one of anynines’ goals is to make PaaS both affordable and compliant to European privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you see, it’s more than just business. Anynines supports selected non-profit open source and charity projects with free hosting, being itself based on the CloudFoundry software! This will allow a fair cost-by-cause-based pricing while still returning something to the community. A sort of Fair Trade hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anynines is operated by enterprise-rails.com, a Rails-focused hosting service and a division of Avarteq. Enterprise-rails.com manages and runs your app in any environment - most customers simply leave the job up to to Enterprise Rails, including hardware and/or OpenStack virtualization, Chef installation automation, monitoring and backups. Just leave it to them and enjoy your apps running like a clockwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The engine behind anynines and enterprise-rails.com is &lt;a href='http://www.avarteq.de/?utm_source=euruko&amp;amp;utm_medium=banner&amp;amp;utm_campaign=selene'&gt;Avarteq&lt;/a&gt;, a German Ruby shop founded in late 2008. It’s been many projects since then and Avarteq has grown from 3 to over 30 people, becoming a rock solid organization with profound Ruby and Ruby on Rails knowledge for both development and operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avarteq loves EuRuKo and would do all their best to keep this magical event alive.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ten days before the CFP closes and...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-13-ten-days-before-the-cfp-closes-and/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-13-ten-days-before-the-cfp-closes-and/</id>
    <published>2013-04-13T19:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T19:25:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;less than 10 days left&lt;/em&gt; before the end of &lt;a href="http://cfp.euruko2013.org/about#dates"&gt;the presentations&amp;#8217; submission period&lt;/a&gt; and we thought it would be nice to share some numbers and some feedback of the process so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoiler:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;it&amp;#8217;s going great and we&amp;#8217;re not even halfway there!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;less than 10 days left&lt;/em&gt; before the end of &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/about#dates'&gt;the presentations&amp;#8217; submission period&lt;/a&gt; and we thought it would be nice to share some numbers and some feedback of the process so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoiler:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;it&amp;#8217;s going great and we&amp;#8217;re not even halfway there!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are some rough, rounded numbers about the process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;52 proposals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(3 withdrawn)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Close to &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/motivation'&gt;200 users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;150 suggestions&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;600 votes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;10000 impressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are some comments regarding the process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intrigued and impressed by @euruko&amp;#8217;s open and social CFP process (&lt;a href='https://twitter.com/pat_shaughnessy/status/317244488877752320'&gt;@pat_shaughnessy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really liked the anonymous approach Euruko was going for (&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/14#suggestion_20'&gt;Bamboo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuRuKo CfP! This time 10 talks are choosen by the community. Hosting conferences was never easier :-P (&lt;a href='https://twitter.com/bovensiepen/status/317293688948658176'&gt;@bovensiepen&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;em&gt;(*)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(*)&lt;/em&gt; No, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;#8217;s not&lt;/strong&gt;!!! See the section below&amp;#8230; :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And here are some number for the application itself:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/euruko2013/vestibule/commits/euruko2013'&gt;500+ commits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/euruko2013/vestibule/graphs/contributors'&gt;12 contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/rubymanor/vestibule/network'&gt;19 forks&lt;/a&gt; of the original &lt;a href='https://github.com/rubymanor/vestibule'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vestibule&lt;/em&gt; app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;At least 5 &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;fremium&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt; services used to make it be live &lt;em&gt;(more on this on another blog post)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are you waiting for? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;Send your proposal now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More tickets, more timezones, more fun...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-12-more-tickets-more-timezones-more-fun/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-12-more-tickets-more-timezones-more-fun/</id>
    <published>2013-04-12T20:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T20:30:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, our first ticket batch sale went…pretty darn fast. But fear not, many more tickets are available for your dereliction and the next ticket sale is coming. Actually two more batches are coming next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be releasing tickets in two batches...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, our first ticket batch sale went&amp;#8230;pretty darn fast. But fear not, many more tickets are available for your dereliction and the next ticket sale is coming. Actually two more batches are coming next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be releasing tickets in two batches. Why two? Well, because we want to cater for different timezones! Our web traffic and sales analytics have shown that we have demand reaching from the US West coast down to Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here is how it is going to work. We will have a batch of tickets released on &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, April 17th at &lt;a href='http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=EuRuKo+2013+2nd+ticket+batch%21&amp;amp;iso=20130417T05'&gt;05:00 UTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; targeting mostly Japan, Australia and US West Coast and another on &lt;strong&gt;Friday, April 19th at &lt;a href='http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=EuRuKo+2013+3rd+ticket+batch%21&amp;amp;iso=20130419T17'&gt;17:00 UTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; targeting again mostly Europe, Africa and US East Coast. Both batches will be available through &lt;a href='https://www.eventora.com/en/Events/euruko-2013-athens'&gt;Eventora&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully this will cover the whole world :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again the ticket price is &lt;strong&gt;60 &amp;#8364;&lt;/strong&gt;. Remember, that you can also buy a &lt;a href='/blog/2013-04-12-above-and-beyond/'&gt;limited supporter ticket&lt;/a&gt; at anytime for &lt;strong&gt;250 &amp;#8364;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any better ideas, please tell us so on Twitter or with a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re soooo excited and soooo doing our best to cater for everybody (or as much as possible)!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Above and beyond...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-12-above-and-beyond/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-12-above-and-beyond/</id>
    <published>2013-04-12T03:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T03:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first ticket batch is &lt;a href="/#tickets"&gt;only some hours away&lt;/a&gt;, the anticipation rises and even though this year I don’t actually have to worry about getting a ticket I still feel excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community participation has so far been very strong with a lot of very interesting...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first ticket batch is &lt;a href='/#tickets'&gt;only some hours away&lt;/a&gt;, the anticipation rises and even though this year I don&amp;#8217;t actually have to worry about getting a ticket I still feel excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community participation has so far been very strong with a lot of very interesting topics covered in our &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org'&gt;CfP&lt;/a&gt;. We are right on track for one more awesome EuRuKo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We committed from the beginning to keep the ticket cost as low as possible and this would certainly have not been possible without our brilliant &lt;a href='/#sponsors'&gt;sponsors&lt;/a&gt;. We also hear from individuals in the community that they would like to contribute as well so we will continue the tradition of offering a limited number of tickets for a higher price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this year we will offer up to 20 Supporter tickets for &lt;strong&gt;250 €&lt;/strong&gt; each for those of you who want to go above and beyond. We know you will not do it to get your name on the &amp;#8220;honor roll&amp;#8221; but we would be ungrateful if we didn&amp;#8217;t do just that. We&amp;#8217;ll even add your fancy company name, along your name, if you want!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tickets will go on sale together with the &lt;a href='/blog/2013-04-08-announcing-the-1st-batch-of-tickets/'&gt;first ticket batch&lt;/a&gt; and we will add the Supporters&amp;#8217; names to the &lt;a href='/#contributors'&gt;EuRuKo 2013&lt;/a&gt; website as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet our sponsors: Wooga</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-10-meet-our-sponsors-wooga/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-10-meet-our-sponsors-wooga/</id>
    <published>2013-04-09T21:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-09T21:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Wooga Logo" src="/images/sponsors/wooga_150x75.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, &lt;a href="http://www.wooga.com/?utm_source=euruko&amp;amp;utm_medium=banner&amp;amp;utm_campaign=aphrodite"&gt;Wooga&lt;/a&gt; supports EuRuKo and we are extremely happy about it! Immediately after last year’s Athens nomination, Wooga contacted us and told us they wanted to support this year’s effort. In doing so, Wooga, took a (heavy) chip off of our shoulders...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Wooga Logo' src='/images/sponsors/wooga_150x75.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, &lt;a href='http://www.wooga.com/?utm_source=euruko&amp;amp;utm_medium=banner&amp;amp;utm_campaign=aphrodite'&gt;Wooga&lt;/a&gt; supports EuRuKo and we are extremely happy about it! Immediately after last year’s Athens nomination, Wooga contacted us and told us they wanted to support this year’s effort. In doing so, Wooga, took a (heavy) chip off of our shoulders. They did so perhaps because members of the Wooga family had organised EuRuKo 2011, perhaps because they are too cool&amp;#8230; we don’t know. But we thank them :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wooga was founded to create computer games for everyone. They develop games with a special focus on emotional characters, good usability and superb localisation in seven languages. No consoles or high-end computers are needed to enjoy Wooga games, making it easy for every player to connect with their friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As they say, they develop social games with love in Berlin. They certainly showed EuRuKo their love again this year and we should all thank them for that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, take a look &lt;a href='http://www.wooga.com/jobs/offers/woogas-future-of-engineering/?utm_source=euruko&amp;amp;utm_medium=banner&amp;amp;utm_campaign=aphrodite'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to see what it takes to join their Engineering team.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet our sponsors: Skroutz</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-09-meet-our-sponsors-skroutz/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-09-meet-our-sponsors-skroutz/</id>
    <published>2013-04-08T21:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-08T21:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skroutz.gr/company/en?from=euruko_blog"&gt;Skroutz&lt;/a&gt; being a Gaia sponsor of EuRuKo was pleasantly inevitable! The Skroutz team has assisted in the preliminary preparations and support and has been waiting for EuRuKo so badly, that we just couldn’t stop them from being our top sponsor. Furthermore...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.skroutz.gr/company/en?from=euruko_blog'&gt;Skroutz&lt;/a&gt; being a Gaia sponsor of EuRuKo was pleasantly inevitable! The Skroutz team has assisted in the preliminary preparations and support and has been waiting for EuRuKo so badly, that we just couldn’t stop them from being our top sponsor. Furthermore, their willingness to become EuRuKo 2013 Gaia sponsor is justified by the fact that there is a thriving Ruby community within the Skroutz team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skroutz.gr began as a hobby project in order to help three ordinary guys find, organize and compare prices for their favorite gadgets. This tech-eCommerce startup came to life in 2005 from a small-scale team of three people. Today, Skroutz.gr is a leading ecommerce brand in Greece consisting of passionate individuals; a diverse range of people with a spectrum of skills and capabilities which tackle the challenges of creating and creatively extending expectations. A team of 40+ top-class professionals make up the working force behind the best price comparison engine in Greece and the number is always growing :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “force” between Skroutz.gr and Ruby is strong. Skroutz.gr is built on RoR and takes full advantage of all the magical features which the Ruby programming language offers. As already mentioned, several members of the Greek Ruby community “live” and enhance their experience within Skroutz by undertaking and creating really amazing projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from Skroutz.gr many ambitious projects were built during the course of the last 8 years, including &lt;a href='http://www.skroutzstore.gr/home'&gt;Skroutzstore&lt;/a&gt; (a user-friendly platform for the creation of a fully operational e-shop in just 10 minutes), &lt;a href='http://mybill.skroutz.gr/'&gt;Skroutz MyBill&lt;/a&gt; (a spin off which extends comparison portfolio to telecommunication services), &lt;a href='http://www.soby.gr/'&gt;Soby&lt;/a&gt; (the first deal aggregator in Greece) and recently &lt;a href='http://www.alve.com/'&gt;Alve.com&lt;/a&gt; (a price comparison engine adjusted to the needs of the Turkish market).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
