<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>EuRuKo 2013 Blog</title>
  <subtitle>The European Ruby Conference 2013 Blog</subtitle>
  <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog</id>
  <link href="http://euruko2013.org/blog"/>
  <link href="http://euruko2013.org/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-04-08T21:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EuRuKo 2013</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet our sponsors: Skroutz</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-09-meet-our-sponsors-skroutz/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-09-meet-our-sponsors-skroutz/</id>
    <published>2013-04-08T21:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-08T21:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.skroutz.gr/company/en?from=euruko_blog"&gt;Skroutz&lt;/a&gt; being a Gaia sponsor of EuRuKo was pleasantly inevitable! The Skroutz team has assisted in the preliminary preparations and support and has been waiting for EuRuKo so badly, that we just couldn’t stop them from being our top sponsors. Furthermore...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.skroutz.gr/company/en?from=euruko_blog'&gt;Skroutz&lt;/a&gt; being a Gaia sponsor of EuRuKo was pleasantly inevitable! The Skroutz team has assisted in the preliminary preparations and support and has been waiting for EuRuKo so badly, that we just couldn’t stop them from being our top sponsors. Furthermore, their willingness to become EuRuKo 2013 Gaia sponsor is justified by the fact that there is a striving Ruby community within the Skroutz team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skroutz.gr began as a hobby project in order to help three ordinary guys to find, organize and compare prices for their favorite gadgets. This tech-eCommerce startup came to life in 2005 from a small-scale team of three people. Today, Skroutz.gr is a leading ecommerce brand in Greece consisting of passionate individuals; a diverse range of people with a spectrum of skills and capabilities which tackle the challenges of creating and creatively extending expectations. A team of 40+ top-class professionals make up the working force behind the best price comparison engine in Greece and the number is always growing :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “force” between Skroutz.gr and Ruby is strong. Skroutz.gr is built on RoR and takes full advantage of all the magical features which Ruby programming language offers. As already mentioned, several members of the Greek Ruby community “live” and enhance their experience within Skroutz by undertaking and creating really amazing projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from Skroutz.gr many ambitious projects were build during the course of the last 8 years, including &lt;a href='http://www.skroutzstore.gr/home'&gt;Skroutzstore&lt;/a&gt; (a user-friendly platform for the creation of a fully operational e-shop in just 10 minutes), &lt;a href='http://mybill.skroutz.gr/'&gt;Skroutz MyBill&lt;/a&gt; (a spin off which extends comparison portfolio to telecommunication services), &lt;a href='http://www.soby.gr/'&gt;Soby&lt;/a&gt; (the first deal aggregator in Greece) and recently &lt;a href='http://www.alve.com/'&gt;Alve.com&lt;/a&gt; (a price comparison engine adjusted to the needs of the Turkish market).&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing the 1st batch of tickets!</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-08-announcing-the-1st-batch-of-tickets/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-08-announcing-the-1st-batch-of-tickets/</id>
    <published>2013-04-07T21:42:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-07T21:42:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi Rubyists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After so many months of preparation, finally the wait is over! So mark the date: tickets go on sale on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 12th of April, &lt;a href="http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=EuRuKo+2013+1st+ticket+batch%21&amp;amp;iso=20130412T14"&gt;14:00 UTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; through &lt;a href="https://www.eventora.com/en/Events/euruko-2013-athens"&gt;eventora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Soon" src="/images/blog/soon.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="how_much"&gt;How much?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticket price is going to be &lt;strong&gt;60€&lt;/strong&gt;. As you may know, EuRuKo has traditionally...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi Rubyists!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After so many months of preparation, finally the wait is over! So mark the date: tickets go on sale on &lt;strong&gt;Friday 12th of April, &lt;a href='http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=EuRuKo+2013+1st+ticket+batch%21&amp;amp;iso=20130412T14'&gt;14:00 UTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; through &lt;a href='https://www.eventora.com/en/Events/euruko-2013-athens'&gt;eventora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Soon' src='/images/blog/soon.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='how_much'&gt;How much?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticket price is going to be &lt;strong&gt;60&amp;#8364;&lt;/strong&gt;. As you may know, EuRuKo has traditionally been a conference with a very reasonable ticket price. The reason is simple: it&amp;#8217;s an event organized by the community for the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this wouldn&amp;#8217;t have been possible without the love of our &lt;a href='/#sponsors'&gt;sponsors&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='how_many_tickets'&gt;How many tickets?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tickets will be released in batches and the first batch is going to be &lt;strong&gt;100 tickets&lt;/strong&gt;. More will follow of course :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id='so_what_do_i_get_with_a_ticket'&gt;So what do I get with a ticket?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly you get to come to a conference where &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;you can decide who is going to speak&lt;/a&gt;! In case you haven’t noticed our call for proposals has opened and we already have many awesome presentations. On top of that, you can meet &lt;a href='/#speakers'&gt;Yukihiro “Matz” Matsumoto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href='/#speakers'&gt;Koichi Sasada&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='/#speakers'&gt;Steve Klabnik&lt;/a&gt; who have already confirmed they are going to speak at this year’s EuRuKo. One last thing: you know that you cannot come to Athens and not have a party! That’s all been taken care of by our &lt;a href='/#sponsors'&gt;sponsors&lt;/a&gt; :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;#8217;t wait to see you in Athens! Until then, you can &lt;a href='/#tickets'&gt;watch the countdown&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Happy April Fools' Day</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-01-happy-april-fools-day/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-01-happy-april-fools-day/</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T20:40:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T20:40:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, obviously nothing of this ever happened. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="/#venue"&gt;Venue&lt;/a&gt; is magnificent as you &amp;#8216;ll witness yourself firsthand when you join us in Athens. Everything is going as planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have lots of work to do before we&amp;#8217;re ready to welcome you to Athens...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, obviously nothing of this ever happened. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href='/#venue'&gt;Venue&lt;/a&gt; is magnificent as you &amp;#8216;ll witness yourself firsthand when you join us in Athens. Everything is going as planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have lots of work to do before we&amp;#8217;re ready to welcome you to Athens this June for EuRuKo 2013, however we are getting there. Our &lt;a href='/blog/2013-03-28-call-for-presentations/'&gt;CFP is open&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;a lot of proposals have been submitted&lt;/a&gt; already. We suggest you get a look at them and vote for those you like and make suggestions to improve the ones you feel need a more thorough description. And why not read the process and &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/about'&gt;submit your own proposal&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really soon, we will announce the &lt;a href='/#tickets'&gt;first batch of tickets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned and follow us closely on &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/euruko'&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, our &lt;a href='/blog/feed.xml'&gt;blog feed&lt;/a&gt; and our &lt;a href='http://eepurl.com/w3D21'&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to reassure you here are a couple more images from the &lt;a href='/'&gt;EuRuKo 2013&lt;/a&gt; awesome Venue:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Badminton Central Scene' src='/images/blog/badminton_center.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Badminton Foyer' src='/images/blog/badminton_foyer.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Badminton Lower Foyer' src='/images/blog/badminton_lower_foyer.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Badminton Console' src='/images/blog/badminton_console.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>We are working hard, but...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-01-we-are-working-hard-but/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-01-we-are-working-hard-but/</id>
    <published>2013-04-01T11:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-01T11:30:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the images below the venue of this year&amp;#8217;s EuRuKo, Badminton Theatre, is being renovated. To be honest, we knew such works were planned, yet we chose to book this amazing &lt;a href="/#venue"&gt;venue&lt;/a&gt; because it was impressive, and with the recently planned...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As you can see from the images below the venue of this year&amp;#8217;s EuRuKo, Badminton Theatre, is being renovated. To be honest, we knew such works were planned, yet we chose to book this amazing &lt;a href='/#venue'&gt;venue&lt;/a&gt; because it was impressive, and with the recently planned renovation it would be really awesome. It was a bold and risky move due to the recent economic difficulties Greece is facing right now (including workers&amp;#8217; strikes). What we wanted, was to have the greatest and biggest venue &lt;a href='http://euruko2013.org'&gt;EuRuKo&lt;/a&gt; had ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Badminton Scene Renovation' src='/images/blog/badminton_scene_renovation.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were promised that the venue would be ready by April, yet when we went there earlier today to inspect the premises we where dumbfounded to discover that the works are midway, with an estimate of late August finish at best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organising committee, along with all of our the amazing volunteers and venue construction crews are working hard to help with construction works. However, we can&amp;#8217;t make any promises yet. We will inform you of our progress as we approach the June deadline. In the mean time &lt;a href='http://twitter.com/euruko'&gt;follow us on twitter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href='http://eepurl.com/w3D21'&gt;sign up for our newsletter&lt;/a&gt; in order to stay informed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Badminton Floor Renovation' src='/images/blog/badminton_floor_renovation.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The committee promises to pull its sleeves up and dive into hard work with the shovel in order to organize EuRuKo 2013 on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your support.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Call for Presentations</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-03-28-call-for-presentations/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-03-28-call-for-presentations/</id>
    <published>2013-03-27T23:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-27T23:30:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are very excited to announce that Call for Presentations for EuRuKo 2013 &lt;a href="http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals"&gt;is now open&lt;/a&gt; and you can send your proposals until &lt;strong&gt;April 23rd&lt;/strong&gt;! We have put a lot of effort in order to create a selection process that will encourage submissions by everyone...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We are very excited to announce that Call for Presentations for EuRuKo 2013 &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;is now open&lt;/a&gt; and you can send your proposals until &lt;strong&gt;April 23rd&lt;/strong&gt;! We have put a lot of effort in order to create a selection process that will encourage submissions by everyone irrespective of publicity, gender, race, domain, etc, guarantee a high quality conference and at the same time be fun for all participants. The process has been refined with feedback from the community and all the details can be found &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/about'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So mark the dates and get engaged:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit your proposal! We are pretty sure that almost everyone has something interesting to share!&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Help refine the proposals: comment, suggest, criticise and show your love :)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Spread the news to the proper channels: your local ruby user groups, your blog, your circles!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;and one last thing: you know how hard it is to find a ticket for EuRuKo usually, right? They tend to sell out in seconds. Well, this year, we are reserving a priority line for active participants in the CfP process along some other goodies that may come later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are you waiting for? &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org'&gt;Join the party&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our contribution...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-03-13-our-contribution/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-03-13-our-contribution/</id>
    <published>2013-03-13T21:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-03-13T21:15:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;From the very first &lt;a href="http://euruko2013.org"&gt;EuRuKo 2013&lt;/a&gt; organisers’ meetup we decided that whatever we were about to do should positively impact the Ruby community. Aside from agreeing that we wanted EuRuKo 2013 to be an amazing conference, we also promised ourselves that...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;From the very first &lt;a href='http://euruko2013.org'&gt;EuRuKo 2013&lt;/a&gt; organisers’ meetup we decided that whatever we were about to do should positively impact the Ruby community. Aside from agreeing that we wanted EuRuKo 2013 to be an amazing conference, we also promised ourselves that even if it didn’t turn out to match our lofty expectations, the community should at least gain something significant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it happens, sometimes such decisions become a tall order when you try to make everything perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of us, in the EuRuKo 2013 committee, spends many hours and even man-days every week in order to analyse and execute our weekly tasks. We are nine people on this committee whose input amounts for many man-days of effort every month. None of us has ever done something like EuRuKo before (not even remotely close), hence we are figuring it out as we go along. We have hired event management professionals to assist us, yet we are involved in every little detail of this conference &amp;#8211;even to the point of exhaustion sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started working on EuRuko 2013 immediately after Athens won the nomination for EuRuKo 2013 in the summer of 2012. Starting from last September, we meet every Wednesday and sometimes Fridays and weekends in order to review, design, allocate and decide on tasks. Since the summer of 2012, team members engage daily in various activities so that progress is made week after week. For example, during the weekends of October and November we were surveying all the top venues in Athens. At other times, members of the team had to skip work to deal with governmental bureaucracy in order found our non-profit company (which we needed in order to deal with suppliers, sponsors etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds scary, but at the beginning we didn’t even know how to approach our weekly task allocation, never mind completing them. Alas, we made many mistakes, even to the point of break-up sometimes. However, we persisted and have now discovered our rhythm and every day we are more confident that we are on the right track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, in numerous occasions, we have asked ourselves what others did before us in order to make EuRuko happen and how problems similar to ours were dealt with. Unfortunately, so many times we have not found adequate answers. This situation made us decide that our hard work should be (re-)used to educate others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, we decided it was not only a good idea, but also our duty to publicly release all EuRuKo conference “execution material”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the hope that subsequent EuRuKos build on our effort and improve on our mistakes and successes we will release, upon the completion of the conference on the 29th of June 2013, all of our documentation, private discussions, decisions, spreadsheets, meeting minutes, supplier contracts, budgets and everything else conference-related that we can think of. This will be our contribution to the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love learning, experimenting and sharing knowledge because above all we believe we can improve our world. We hope that the honour, which the Ruby community has bestowed upon this unfairly tarnished part of our globe, can be turned into tangible benefits for everyone inside and outside of the Ruby community! So, thank you for your trust and please accept our contribution, it is coming soon&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
