<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>EuRuKo 2013 Blog</title>
  <subtitle>The European Ruby Conference 2013 Blog</subtitle>
  <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog</id>
  <link href="http://euruko2013.org/blog"/>
  <link href="http://euruko2013.org/blog/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2013-04-17T09:55:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>EuRuKo 2013</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet our sponsors: Metaquark</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-17-meet-our-sponsors-metaquark/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-17-meet-our-sponsors-metaquark/</id>
    <published>2013-04-17T09:55:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T09:55:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Metaquark Logo" src="/images/sponsors/metaquark_150x75.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the team at &lt;a href="http://metaquark.de/"&gt;Metaquark&lt;/a&gt; shared every mobile developer’s experience. This of the difficulty of designing, building, releasing and maintaining mobile apps. In this experience, many manual steps had to be followed repeatedly in order...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Metaquark Logo' src='/images/sponsors/metaquark_150x75.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a long time, the team at &lt;a href='http://metaquark.de/'&gt;Metaquark&lt;/a&gt; shared every mobile developer&amp;#8217;s experience. This of the difficulty of designing, building, releasing and maintaining mobile apps. In this experience, many manual steps had to be followed repeatedly in order to test, publish and then collect application usage information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It got more complicated every time they added support for a new mobile operating system, because none of them are alike as we all know. It got even worse when they tried to do all of that in a distributed team, with very few tools that were built to support such team structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then it was when when they set out to make developing mobile apps a lot easier. Metaquark&amp;#8217;s mobile enterprise application platform called ‘AppFresh Mobile’ is a central service for large and small companies which helps manage the life-cycle of mobile applications. AppFresh Mobile includes distributed cloud builds for all mobile platforms, application security policies, distribution of applications to handsets using a custom enterprise applications store and extensive monitoring to help improve the quality of applications delivered to employees and customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Metaquark work with a great variety of technologies to implement their mobile cross-platform and cloud strategy. Not surprisingly, their core platform is powered by Ruby and Rails. Their platform can either be deployed in a highly scalable Metaquark cloud setup, or directly at the customer site. Metaquark are small but fast growing. Their team and their vision are backed by their strategic investor and strong partner Software AG. Together they deliver mobile technologies and projects for some of the biggest enterprises all around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that, but Metaquark are &lt;a href='http://metaquark.de/jobs/'&gt;hiring!&lt;/a&gt; They suggest that if you&amp;#8217;re looking for a challenge, they are the right place for you! The place to work on technology, concepts and strategies, think in new ways, be creative and take over great challenges. You may join them in one of their offices in Berlin and Leipzig (Germany) and make cross-platform mobile application life-cycle management available to all enterprises which develop mobile applications. From managing, building and signing mobile applications in the cloud to full featured application and device management on the mobile client, you name it, they are working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help development teams all over the world develop better apps and save time by using AppFresh Mobile!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Calling All Ruby Brigades</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-17-calling-all-ruby-brigades/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-17-calling-all-ruby-brigades/</id>
    <published>2013-04-17T05:39:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-17T05:39:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first time I attended EuRuKo was 2008. I managed to get a talk accepted so I didn&amp;#8217;t have to worry about a ticket. Every year after that I fell victim to what I have recently seen called the &amp;#8220;EuRuKo ticket fight&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference is popular and...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first time I attended EuRuKo was 2008. I managed to get a talk accepted so I didn&amp;#8217;t have to worry about a ticket. Every year after that I fell victim to what I have recently seen called the &amp;#8220;EuRuKo ticket fight&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference is popular and tickets sell out in record speeds. It&amp;#8217;s a pleasant problem for a conference organizer, but we are not professional conference organizers! We are part of the community and have ourselves been subjected to the same frustration of not being able to secure a ticket for the conference we love. So we will introduce a couple of different ways to distribute tickets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of these is something our Dutch friends established last year for EuRuKo 2012: Tickets reserved for Ruby user groups. Interesting fact: Almost half of this year&amp;#8217;s organizing committee got tickets for the Amsterdam conference this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For EuRuKo 2013 there will be reserved tickets for Ruby user groups. If you are a member of a Ruby user group and would like tickets then please fill in the &lt;a href='https://docs.google.com/a/euruko2013.org/spreadsheet/viewform?formkey=dFhXcDQtQlQ5SGZJTDNzaEZCZEx5R1E6MQ'&gt;form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give us the name of the user group along the number of tickets you would like and any information that will help us verify your claim . The deadline for submissions is the 26th April. We cannot guarantee that you will get all the tickets you ask for and we do recommend to try and get your ticket from the last batch to go on sale &lt;a href='http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=EuRuKo+2013+3rd+ticket+batch%21&amp;amp;iso=20130419T17'&gt;Friday, April 19th at 17:00UTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there are requests for more tickets then the number we have reserved we will distrbute them evenly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User groups are the heart of every local communitty and EuRuKo is the best venue for the local communities to connect, communicate and cooperate. Join us in making EuRuKo 2013 one of the best Ruby conferences!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meet our sponsors: Avarteq</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-16-meet-our-sponsors-avarteq/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-16-meet-our-sponsors-avarteq/</id>
    <published>2013-04-16T10:49:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-16T10:49:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Avarteq Logo" src="/images/sponsors/avarteq_200x100.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anynines is an upcoming Heroku-like PaaS written in Ruby. A hosting that grows with your apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks from anynines see their job as terribly important - many developers put pet apps to PaaS providers, yet introducing larger installations is often...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='Avarteq Logo' src='/images/sponsors/avarteq_200x100.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anynines is an upcoming Heroku-like PaaS written in Ruby. A hosting that grows with your apps!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folks from anynines see their job as terribly important - many developers put pet apps to PaaS providers, yet introducing larger installations is often way too expensive and complicated. That’s why it’s going to start as non-freemium, pay-as-you-go service. Additionaly, one of anynines’ goals is to make PaaS both affordable and compliant to European privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you see, it’s more than just business. Anynines supports selected non-profit open source and charity projects with free hosting, being itself based on the CloudFoundry software! This will allow a fair cost-by-cause-based pricing while still returning something to the community. A sort of Fair Trade hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anynines is operated by enterprise-rails.com, a Rails-focused hosting service and a division of Avarteq. Enterprise-rails.com manages and runs your app in any environment - most customers simply leave the job up to to Enterprise Rails, including hardware and/or OpenStack virtualization, Chef installation automation, monitoring and backups. Just leave it to them and enjoy your apps running like a clockwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The engine behind anynines and enterprise-rails.com is &lt;a href='http://www.avarteq.de/?utm_source=euruko&amp;amp;utm_medium=banner&amp;amp;utm_campaign=selene'&gt;Avarteq&lt;/a&gt;, a German Ruby shop founded in late 2008. It’s been many projects since then and Avarteq has grown from 3 to over 30 people, becoming a rock solid organization with profound Ruby and Ruby on Rails knowledge for both development and operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Avarteq loves EuRuKo and would do all their best to keep this magical event alive.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ten days before the CFP closes and...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-13-ten-days-before-the-cfp-closes-and/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-13-ten-days-before-the-cfp-closes-and/</id>
    <published>2013-04-13T19:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-13T19:25:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;less than 10 days left&lt;/em&gt; before the end of &lt;a href="http://cfp.euruko2013.org/about#dates"&gt;the presentations&amp;#8217; submission period&lt;/a&gt; and we thought it would be nice to share some numbers and some feedback of the process so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoiler:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;it&amp;#8217;s going great and we&amp;#8217;re not even halfway there!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here...&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;less than 10 days left&lt;/em&gt; before the end of &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/about#dates'&gt;the presentations&amp;#8217; submission period&lt;/a&gt; and we thought it would be nice to share some numbers and some feedback of the process so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoiler:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;it&amp;#8217;s going great and we&amp;#8217;re not even halfway there!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are some rough, rounded numbers about the process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;52 proposals&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;(3 withdrawn)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Close to &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/motivation'&gt;200 users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;150 suggestions&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;600 votes&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;10000 impressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are some comments regarding the process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intrigued and impressed by @euruko&amp;#8217;s open and social CFP process (&lt;a href='https://twitter.com/pat_shaughnessy/status/317244488877752320'&gt;@pat_shaughnessy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really liked the anonymous approach Euruko was going for (&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals/14#suggestion_20'&gt;Bamboo&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EuRuKo CfP! This time 10 talks are choosen by the community. Hosting conferences was never easier :-P (&lt;a href='https://twitter.com/bovensiepen/status/317293688948658176'&gt;@bovensiepen&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;em&gt;(*)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(*)&lt;/em&gt; No, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;#8217;s not&lt;/strong&gt;!!! See the section below&amp;#8230; :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And here are some number for the application itself:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/euruko2013/vestibule/commits/euruko2013'&gt;500+ commits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/euruko2013/vestibule/graphs/contributors'&gt;12 contributors&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/rubymanor/vestibule/network'&gt;19 forks&lt;/a&gt; of the original &lt;a href='https://github.com/rubymanor/vestibule'&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vestibule&lt;/em&gt; app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;At least 5 &lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;fremium&amp;#8221;&lt;/em&gt; services used to make it be live &lt;em&gt;(more on this on another blog post)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what are you waiting for? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org/proposals'&gt;Send your proposal now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>More tickets, more timezones, more fun...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-12-more-tickets-more-timezones-more-fun/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-12-more-tickets-more-timezones-more-fun/</id>
    <published>2013-04-12T20:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T20:30:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, our first ticket batch sale went…pretty darn fast. But fear not, many more tickets are available for your dereliction and the next ticket sale is coming. Actually two more batches are coming next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be releasing tickets in two batches...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, our first ticket batch sale went&amp;#8230;pretty darn fast. But fear not, many more tickets are available for your dereliction and the next ticket sale is coming. Actually two more batches are coming next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be releasing tickets in two batches. Why two? Well, because we want to cater for different timezones! Our web traffic and sales analytics have shown that we have demand reaching from the US West coast down to Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here is how it is going to work. We will have a batch of tickets released on &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, April 17th at &lt;a href='http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=EuRuKo+2013+2nd+ticket+batch%21&amp;amp;iso=20130417T05'&gt;05:00 UTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; targeting mostly Japan, Australia and US West Coast and another on &lt;strong&gt;Friday, April 19th at &lt;a href='http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/fixedtime.html?msg=EuRuKo+2013+3rd+ticket+batch%21&amp;amp;iso=20130419T17'&gt;17:00 UTC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; targeting again mostly Europe, Africa and US East Coast. Both batches will be available through &lt;a href='https://www.eventora.com/en/Events/euruko-2013-athens'&gt;Eventora&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully this will cover the whole world :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again the ticket price is &lt;strong&gt;60 &amp;#8364;&lt;/strong&gt;. Remember, that you can also buy a &lt;a href='/blog/2013-04-12-above-and-beyond/'&gt;limited supporter ticket&lt;/a&gt; at anytime for &lt;strong&gt;250 &amp;#8364;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any better ideas, please tell us so on Twitter or with a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re soooo excited and soooo doing our best to cater for everybody (or as much as possible)!&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Above and beyond...</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/blog/2013-04-12-above-and-beyond/"/>
    <id>http://euruko2013.org/blog/2013-04-12-above-and-beyond/</id>
    <published>2013-04-12T03:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2013-04-12T03:00:00Z</updated>
    <author>
      <name>EuRuKo 2013 Team</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first ticket batch is &lt;a href="/#tickets"&gt;only some hours away&lt;/a&gt;, the anticipation rises and even though this year I don’t actually have to worry about getting a ticket I still feel excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community participation has so far been very strong with a lot of very interesting...&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first ticket batch is &lt;a href='/#tickets'&gt;only some hours away&lt;/a&gt;, the anticipation rises and even though this year I don&amp;#8217;t actually have to worry about getting a ticket I still feel excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community participation has so far been very strong with a lot of very interesting topics covered in our &lt;a href='http://cfp.euruko2013.org'&gt;CfP&lt;/a&gt;. We are right on track for one more awesome EuRuKo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We committed from the beginning to keep the ticket cost as low as possible and this would certainly have not been possible without our brilliant &lt;a href='/#sponsors'&gt;sponsors&lt;/a&gt;. We also hear from individuals in the community that they would like to contribute as well so we will continue the tradition of offering a limited number of tickets for a higher price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this year we will offer up to 20 Supporter tickets for &lt;strong&gt;250 €&lt;/strong&gt; each for those of you who want to go above and beyond. We know you will not do it to get your name on the &amp;#8220;honor roll&amp;#8221; but we would be ungrateful if we didn&amp;#8217;t do just that. We&amp;#8217;ll even add your fancy company name, along your name, if you want!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tickets will go on sale together with the &lt;a href='/blog/2013-04-08-announcing-the-1st-batch-of-tickets/'&gt;first ticket batch&lt;/a&gt; and we will add the Supporters&amp;#8217; names to the &lt;a href='/#contributors'&gt;EuRuKo 2013&lt;/a&gt; website as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
